vin-info.com 2018-11-16

# Privacy policy

Your personal data is administered by VIN-Info Sp. z o.o. (ul. Modelarska 18, 40-142 Katowice, Polska,  [support@vin-info.com](mailto:support@vin-info.com) ).   
We may process your data (IP address, browser and OS and approximate GPS location): \- if required by our legal interest, for statistical purposes and to manage the web site, for the period until we complete our statistical analysis, but no longer than for 3 years since the year in which the data was acquired; \- for legally justified reasons, in course of direct marketing of our services, including with your consent, using profiling to screen any future advertisements for our services in other web sites, throughout the lifetime of the site or by the time your consent is withdrawn.  
We cooperate with: marketing service providers, web browsers, social networks, providers of tools for statistics and social network management, host companies, who can receive this data from us (data receivers). No data can be transferred to any non-EU country or entity, other than those accepted by EU law.  
You are not obliged to provide us your data, but when you refuse to do so, the site may function incorrectly. You have access to your data, for correction, deletion or to impose restrictions on processing. You can also protest against processing or any transfer of your data. You can withdraw your consent for processing your data at any time, but this will have no effect on legality of data processing completed before your consent was withdrawn. You have the right to lodge your protest to the Chairman of the Poland’s Personal Data Protection Office or his counterpart in any other EU country.  
The web site may use cookies and other similar technologies in aforementioned purposes. You accept cookies by choosing the respective settings in your browser. More about our data processing rules and browser settings can be found in our [Privacy Policy].

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of each Website user. 

VIN-Info sp. z o.o. (ul. Modelarska 18, 40-142 Katowice, Poland, support@vin-info.com) is the controller of your personal data. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our treatment of your personal information, or if you want to instruct us with respect to your personal data, please contact us to the above mentioned e-mail address. 

**I. Processed personal data, legal basis and periods of processing**

We may collect, store and process the following kinds of personal data: 

\- information about your computer and about your visits to and use of the Website (in particular: your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, time and length of visit, page views, website navigation), which we process on the basis of our legitimate interests with the purpose of statistics and administration of the Website, and direct marketing during the period, respectively, until the end of the statistical analysis or until the end of the marketing activities, however, not longer than during the period of 3 years from the end of the year when the data was collected; 

\- information necessary to render services available on the Website (in particular: e-mail address, name and surname, address, tax identification number, bank account number, transaction number, content of the shopping cart) and information connected with registration on the Website (in particular e-mail address, login, password), which we process on the basis of performance of a contract defined in the Terms and Conditions with the purpose of conclusion of the contract, enforcing it and terminating it, and on the basis of our legitimate interests with the purpose of enforcement of claims connected with the contract and to ensure security of the data provided by the users under the registration on the Website, during the period of 10 years from the end of the year of completion of the contract or its termination , but not less than till completion of exercising the claims connected with the contract and expiration of the limitation period for claims, and on the basis of the legal obligations stipulated in the Accountancy Act and in the Tax Law during the periods indicated in these regulations (currently pursuant to Article 74 of the Accountancy Act and Article 32 § 1 of the Tax Law that period consists of 5 years from the beginning of the year following the financial year which is related to the respective data); 

\- information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing the Website news services, in particular email notifications and/or newsletters (e-mail address), which we process on the basis of your consent during the period when these services are active and/or until the consent is withdrawn; 

\- information necessary for communication with you (in particular e-mail address, name and surname, phone number and communication content), which we process on the basis of our legitimate interests with the purpose of communicating with you and to defend us from claims, during the period of 10 years from the end of the year in which the communication ended. 

**II. Cookies**

The Website uses cookies which make us possible to adjust the Website to the needs of its users by preparing and analysing of statistics of use of the Website by them. The statistics do not refer to personal data of the Website users. 

A cookie consists of information sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser. The information is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser. 

We use both "session" cookies and "persistent" cookies on the Website. We will use the session cookies to: keep track of you whilst you navigate the Website. We will use the persistent cookies to: enable the Website to recognise you when you visit the Website. 

Session cookies will be deleted from your computer when you close your browser. Persistent cookies will remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date. 

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of the Website. Google Analytics generates statistical and other information about the Website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information generated relating to the Website is used to create reports about the use of the Website. Google will store this information. Google's privacy policy is available at: http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html. 

Third parties, in particular our advertisers/payment services providers may also send you cookies pursuant to the rules stated on their websites. 

The consent to use cookies from the Website is made through the options chosen by you in the settings of your browser. Most browsers allow you to reject all cookies or to reject just third party cookies. For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookies by clicking "Tools", "Internet Options", "Privacy", and selecting "Block all cookies" using the sliding selector. Blocking all cookies will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites. 

**III. Recipients of data**

We may disclose information about you to any of our employees, officers and associates, insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes as set out in this Privacy Policy, however, they are obliged to secure the data properly. 

We cooperate with: marketing companies, web search engines, companies providing tools for statistical analysis and operation of social networks, web hosting companies, accountancy companies, providers of the invoice services, payment services providers, law firms, car valuers. We may transfer to them your data with the purposes mentioned in the Section I above, therefore they should be considered as data recipients. 

The data may be transferred outside the EU, however, only to the states or entities approved under the EU law, in particular to the entities from US which participate in the Privacy Shield project (see https://www.privacyshield.gov/). 

In addition, we may disclose your personal information to public authorities to the extent that we are required to do so by law. 

**IV. Users rights**

As a user of the Website you have a right to request from the controller access to and rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing or to object to processing as well as the right to data portability. In order to make use of those rights please contact us trough the contact form on the Website or to the e-mail address. 

As a user of the Website you have right to lodge a complaint regarding our processing of you data with the Inspector President of the Office of Protection of Personal Data (Prezes Urzędu Ochrony Danych Osobowych) in Poland or its equivalent in other EU Member State, in accordance with your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement. 

**V. Security of your personal information**

We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. 

We will store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password- and firewall- protected) servers. All electronic transactions you make to or receive from us and sensitive and/or private data exchange will be encrypted using SSL technology. 

Due to its nature data transmission over the Internet is inherently insecure. However, we use various measures in order to secure your data. If you would like to provide us with recommendation regarding the security, we encourage you to contact us trough the contact form or to our e-mail address. 

**VI. Third party websites**

The Website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third party websites. These websites, including their content and links, may be constantly changing and may have their own privacy policies and other regulations, which we recommend to read.
